<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on NandoTech</title>
    <link>https://nandotech.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on NandoTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>info@nandotech.com (Fernando Rodriguez)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>info@nandotech.com (Fernando Rodriguez)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nandotech.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with AngularJS 1.x</title>
      <link>https://nandotech.github.io/post/2016-06-11-getting-started-angularjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>info@nandotech.com (Fernando Rodriguez)</author>
      <guid>https://nandotech.github.io/post/2016-06-11-getting-started-angularjs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently took the Pluralsight course AngularJS: Get Started by Scott Allen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want the tl;dr early, it’s totally worth it and really starts to give you a pretty decent working knowledge of AngularJS, and what’s better yet: you build an actual working application in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did my own tweaks with the UI, minor deviations as well as selecting my own theme, but otherwise it’s pretty cool to see just how easy it is to create beautiful AngularJS apps tied to an API that turns standard JSON responses with little heavy lifting. Powerful built-in data binding and directives like ng-repeat have me sold on Angular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out my Plunker with the working “Github Viewer” application. &lt;a href=&#34;http://plnkr.co/vmqj8K&#34;&gt;Link to plnkr.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also available on GitHub, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nandotech/umgbeta&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nandotech/umgbeta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launches a page where you type any github username you’d like to look up and returns projects sorted by stars along with the user’s avatar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*7h_r_uTlUc68krRf.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; /&gt;\n\n\n\nYou should also be able to view the source code. Feel free to make any comments! Special thanks again to Scott Allen &amp;amp; Pluralsight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with Angular 2.0 coming, I’ll bear with the growing pains. There’s a bright future ahead for this stack and developing with it is a joy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Priorities Over Feelings</title>
      <link>https://nandotech.github.io/post/2016-06-10-priorities-over-feelings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>info@nandotech.com (Fernando Rodriguez)</author>
      <guid>https://nandotech.github.io/post/2016-06-10-priorities-over-feelings/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;let-s-be-honest&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be honest.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;most-people-are-not-very-good-at-this&#34;&gt;Most  people are not very good at this.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, it almost sounds dumb, like some cliche you hear from motivational speakers on a regular basis. &lt;strong&gt;Far from that&lt;/strong&gt;, it is an extremely astute articulation of a decision one as an entrepreneur and a business owner has to consciously make on a daily basis.\n\nOn a daily basis, we must choose to put our &lt;em&gt;priorities&lt;/em&gt; over our &lt;em&gt;feelings&lt;/em&gt;.  Again, not a difficult concept to grasp.  However, it is a much more difficult concept to truthfully embrace whole-heartedly because let&amp;rsquo;s face it: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/intense-emotions-and-strong-feelings/201012/it-or-not-emotions-will-drive-the-decisions-you&#34;&gt;humans are not very good at controlling emotion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://successyeti.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/TSBB_Frustration-440x293.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Strong emotions&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are.  Relegated to the endless tug-of-war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or are we?  After serious reflection I realized that there is absolutely no reason to be or stay a slave to your emotions like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had an extremely difficult client.  My company prides itself on providing excellent customer service, going so far as to even provide our regular clients slack channels where they have unfettered access to us pretty much &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself nearly having a stroke and moreover negatively impacting my relationship with my client (who luckily also happens to be a friend, or he probably would have fired me already) on a daily basis.  Every day I was allowing my feelings to get in the way of my priorities.\n\nThis doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that it is going to be easy.  As a matter of fact, I had to take some rather &lt;strong&gt;drastic&lt;/strong&gt; measures but in the end it has worked out for the best.  We&amp;rsquo;ve reached the end of the week&amp;ndash;neither one of us (my client or I) wants to kill each other and he has gotten better customer service this week than he has in several weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be wondering, what changed?  I put my PRIORITIES over my FEELINGS.  Thanks to the wonders of technology: &lt;em&gt;I shut down the Slack channel and deactivated my friend&amp;rsquo;s slack account&lt;/em&gt;.  He no longer has the ability to distract us while we&amp;rsquo;re working or frustrate me with questions that I must impulsively answer.  Impulsive in that I tended to overreact, so I  had to change the dynamic of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our relationship has never been better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going From Zero to One</title>
      <link>https://nandotech.github.io/post/2016-02-27-going-from-zero-to-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>info@nandotech.com (Fernando Rodriguez)</author>
      <guid>https://nandotech.github.io/post/2016-02-27-going-from-zero-to-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chances are I’m also not the first person you’ve heard this from, either. This is one of the very few books that truly is a must-read for anyone who calls themselves a business owner, entrepreneur or anyone even considering the prospect of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out my Amazon Prime subscription came with a free few Audible credits. Naturally, the temptation of free being too much to resist, I grabbed a copy of Peter Thiel’s Zero to One.
Peter Thiel co-founded PayPal in 1998 with Max Levchin and later Elon Musk and served as its CEO before going on to co-found Palantir and many other successful investments and ventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/0*xYzzIwDiflb5ndSD.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Zero to One&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listened to the entire book in the last 30 hours and am preparing myself for a second listen. To say that Mr. Thiel provides sage advice to any entrepreneur or businessperson considering it is a gross understatement. Some of what you read (hear?) may sound a bit grandiose, but the author manages to have these great visions always be firmly rooted in really simple fundamental truths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book opens posing the contrarian question that he poses at every interview he has, “What very important truth do very few people agree with you on?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it. At once, the question asks you to identify an important truth (daunting, on its own) while adding that very few people agree with you on it. Outright asking someone to voice what is inherently an unpopular opinion by definition can be an uncomfortable question to ask. But an important one nonetheless.
Peter Thiel and Blake Masters provide us examples of good and bad answers to this question, as well as their own responses. Mr. Thiel postulates that monopolies are good for business while perfect competition stifles it. Something naturally opposed to what we are taught our entire lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer? We are on the verge of having a technically illiterate generation if we do not begin to close the tech skills gap immediately and teach computer programming as a core subject beginning in grade school. I haven’t exactly polled it. Does that qualify as unpopular? Is the idea that today’s system of education is failing our youth not something many people would agree with me on? I’m not sure.\nThere’s one thing I am sure of. We must go from Zero to One.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little bit about us.</title>
      <link>https://nandotech.github.io/post/2015-11-27-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>info@nandotech.com (Fernando Rodriguez)</author>
      <guid>https://nandotech.github.io/post/2015-11-27-first-post/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are just 2 super geeks who blog here in our spare time because we love what we do. We are software developers and telephony solution experts in South Florida. What’s more, if our experiences and (sometimes) horror stories can entertain you, or better yet, help guide you through your next project then we feel like we’ve given back to the community and are no longer just consumers taking in information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formally, we are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nandotech.com&#34;&gt;NandoTech, Inc.&lt;/a&gt; Software developers and telephony solution experts. Also, a full service IT company located in South Florida, catering mostly to call centers and specializing in the .NET stack for our software. About mid-way through 2015 we decided NandoTech had something to offer the market that does not exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are. Working gruelingly long weeks, working all hours of the night, always concerned about customer x, y or z and that they have everything they need for their business to operate smoothly. And we absolutely love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be posting relevant articles mostly pertaining to software development, startups, VoIP/Telephony systems as well as ASP.NET MVC &amp;amp; web dev. As a general rule, there is nothing that we DON’T do–we just have our preferences and opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preferences and opinions which by the way are very much our own, and do not necessarily reflect those of NandoTech, Inc or any of its shareholders.
At NandoTech, we are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fernando-rodriguez-president-ceo-software-development&#34;&gt;Fernando Rodriguez, President/CEO — Software Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;arron-mayers-vice-president-technical-development&#34;&gt;Arron Mayers — Vice President — Technical Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nandotech-inc&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;NandoTech, Inc&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we are just 2 super geeks trying to help others like us.
Hope you enjoy the blog. Our passion to always keep learning new things keeps us inspired, and your support just might keep us fed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>